GILBERT ONYENWEZI

◆ 19 Exeter Road ◆ Fords, NJ 08863 ◆ (908) 906-7871 ◆ Trebligism@gmail.com

SUMMARY

An executive with over fifteen years of success driving profits, quality, and customer satisfaction to record levels. Background includes operations leadership roles at Amazon, United Geophysical, Ferriesmart and Manaksia Industries. Overseeing multi-shift, multi-plant operations, including experiences in manufacturing, production & supply chain environments with emphasis on project coordination and management.

CORE COMPETENCIES

- Manage day to day operation in a warehouse and distribution environment with goal of serving customer needs.
- Proactively identify and lead process improvement projects to solve complex problems across the network
- Develop, monitor, and implement processes required to effectively manage company's current activities and operations and plan for growth.
- Developed and maintain system of identifying, reporting, and reducing slow moving and surplus inventory and increasing overall inventory turns.
- Manage carrier relationships at a local, regional, and national level and identify opportunities for improvement through ongoing carrier communication.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

FERRIESMART GLOBAL WAREHOUSE MANAGER - March 2020 - Till Date

- Manage and lead the Workplace Planning Managers that are a single point of contact with Business Units.
- Manage eCommerce Fulfillment day-to-day operations by reviewing open orders and collaborating with teams to get orders out within timelines.
- Presents & negotiates with the business units to implement plans aligned with corporate guideline while meeting business requirements.
- Manage the day-to-day business operations of eCommerce Fulfillment, including reviewing open orders and collaborating with teams to ship them out.
- Manages relocations including the development and execution of project planning activities, timing of group moves/relocations, migration and phasing plans, stack and block plans, architectural test-fits and relocations.
- Evaluate the performance of logistics partners and report any issues or exceptions to the appropriate
 parties for resolution. Collaborate with Supply Chain team and Category Managers to improve backorder,
 EOL, replacement/RMA, and order exceptions to pro-actively prevent order issues.

 Partner with Workplace Portfolio Strategy team to develop and own business forecast, including headcount, to accurately track space needs that is supported by excellent data, trend analysis, possible outcomes.

- Track flaws and provide a complete reconciliation of open orders in order to determine the main cause.
- Collaboration with the customer service team to identify and address customer concerns and to develop initiatives that will improve the customer experience.
- Partner and advisor to management within business groups on all workplace planning activities.
- Regularly represents company at meetings with carrier representatives for purposes of managing performance and identifying mutual solutions

<u>AMAZON – NEW JERSEY</u>

YARD SPECIALIST > TRANSPORTATION SPECIALIST (EWR5 - SC) - January 2019 - March 2020

- Continual, tactical communication with external customers (Carriers, Vendors/Suppliers) and internal customers (Retail, Finance, Software Support, Fulfillment Centers).
- Lead initiatives to re-engineer business processes and identify and eliminate root causes of defects in order to drive efficiency in Amazon's transportation operations.
- Primary manager responsible for driving performance in key metrics such as safety, on-time delivery/pickup,
 rejections and compliance
- Review the work forecasts and determine productivity requirements to produce during the day to meet the overall building objectives.
- Partner with other Area Managers to balance labor ensuring balanced operations and efficient shift.
- Manage carrier performance against Perfect VRID expectations (Tender accept, OT to pick/depart, OT to Destination, App Compliance, EDI compliance, Reject Rate, Case Response Time)
- Responsible for inbound performance across key metrics: CARP Compliance, EDI Compliance, On-Time, Case
 Management, No Call No Show
- Manage carrier engagement, driving carrier value proposition: Revenue, Tractor Utilization, Tour Quality
- Partner with Transportation Operations Teams and Building Operations' Senior leadership to drive process improvements that reduce: Misloads / Trailer Damage / Gate Delays / FC Loads Delays
- Regularly represents company at meetings with carrier representatives for purposes of managing performance and identifying mutual solutions.

AMAZON - NEW JERSEY

Area Manager — January 2018 – December 2018

• Contribute to the management of 100-120 associates, delegating duties and monitoring performance (40 sorters, 60 packers, 5 leads, 5 problems solve, 5 SLAM/KO, 5 box replenish)

- Provide quarterly rates and follow up with bottom performers to remove barriers
- Ensure associates follow Amazon's safety requirements, quality standards, and policies at all times.
- Communicate effectively with associates to offer feedback and guidance when needed
- Deliver ADAPT feedback to ensure all associates are 100% to plan or administer corrective action
- Ensure no CPT's are missed while monitoring dwells and problem solve buckets to give off positive handoff
- Monitoring WIP, recirc and tray count to avoid gridlock/AGL to maintain constant flow with all departments
- Send EOS WASH daily recapping everything that happened throughout the shift
- AMAZON NEW JERSEY

AMBASSADOR > SUPERVISOR > NARC TEAM — January 2017 — December 2018

- Broke the problem solve bucket record for AFE in EWR4 with 11 units running 18 walls and 83 units during peak
 of 2017 running 22 walls (AFE 2.0)
- Created a problem solve guideline to help guide other shifts on how to run problem solve due to having very low risk of missing CPT's (delegating, motivating, and holding everyone accountable)
- Trained/mentored new area managers (5) and supervisors (7) due to being the top tier supervisor
- Helped launch two buildings LGA9 running AFE 3.0 and ACY1 running AFE 3.5
- Helped train and develop 5 team leads into supervisors due to coaching, check lists and 1:1's every month to keep a track of personal growth and development.
- Held the best quality/DPMO in LGA9 since launch with under one mistake per hour while sorting 8-14 thousand units per hour. (DPMO started at 7000 at launch and has dropped down to 1000 in 3 months)

FERRIESMART / JAND HOMES — Lagos, NG - October 2010 – June 2016 <u>Chief Operating Officer</u> — October 2010 – June 2016

- Directs internal operations to achieve budgeted results and other financial criteria, and to preserve the capital funds invested in the enterprise.
- Participates in the development and preparation of short-term and long-range plans and budgets based upon broad organization goals and objectives.
- Directs the development and installation of procedures and controls, to promote communication and adequate information flow, and thereby solidify management control and direction of the enterprise.
- Develops and establishes operating policies consistent with the CEO's broad policies and objectives and insures
 their adequate execution. Appraises and evaluates the results of overall operations regularly and systematically,
 and reports these results to the CEO
- Develops and maintains a sound plan of organization. Establishes policies to ensure adequate management development and to provide for capable management succession for those functions/business units falling under my responsibility.

• Directs the development and establishment of adequate and equitable personnel policies throughout the organization, including compensation policies and employee benefit plans

WORLD BANK AND LAGOS EKO P ROJECT— Lagos, NG - September 2010 – August 2014 **Volunteer Teacher** — Life Skills

- The Lagos Eko Secondary Education Project (EKO Project) is a Lagos state program supported by The World Bank with overall aim of improving the learning outcomes in public junior and senior secondary schools in Lagos state. It was an amazing experience that I will continue to cherish for the rest of my life!
- I taught pupils in Junior (JSS 1-3) and Senior Secondary (SS1-3) schools in Public School on Tuesdays and Thursdays for 45 minutes on each Day
- I volunteered in five (5) Schools in the Gbagada area of Lagos state. I taught Decision Making, Time
 Management, Negotiation Skill, Entrepreneurial Initiatives and Information and Communications Technology.

Notable Achievements:

- Introduced the Life Skills categories and developed the curriculum for the program
- Won the Governors award for the best overall volunteer for 2010, 2011, 2012, 2013 and 2014.
- Was made an Ambassador for the Project.
- Won overall bet life skill volunteer and Lagos State Ministry of Education District II Best Volunteer

UNITED GEOPHYSICAL NIGERIA LIMITED — Lagos, NG - October 2003 – 2008 **Operations Manager** — October 2003 – 2008

- Work closely with the UGBG BISO leadership team on projects and initiatives, outlined by our key strategic priorities.
- Build excellent working relationships with cross-functional teams and stakeholders of all levels to achieve project goals and drive opportunities to streamline processes and create efficiencies
- Manage executive slide development, including building from scratch, adapting existing formats, clarifying requirements, incorporating updates, and providing feedback.
- Manage communication flow to ensure accuracy and transparency with internal and external stakeholders; help create the vision for the team and architect communication strategies.
- Facilitate timely execution of data / materials collection for leadership meetings, reviews, and presentations.
- Recognize criticality of time sensitive turnaround times for executive materials and requests; ensure all timelines
 are met or exceeded.
- Act as the Subject Matter Expert for manage the current and forecasted resources needed across the team.
- Responsible for all activities related to employee engagement and culture.

MANAKSIA INDUSTRIES NIGERIA LIMITED

Quality Control Manager/Development Executive — October 2001 – 2003

<u>Plant Engineer/Production Supervisor/Production Manager</u> - 1997 – 2000

 Managed activities of 24 people, functioning as the hub for 4 separate plants to complete projects that involved staff within different offices nationwide.

- Organized projects setting up the materials to be used, establishing timelines, managing customer relationships, developing workflow patterns necessary to the type of print production required. (i.e. digital or offset). Produced and recommended timelines while upselling products and materials prior to production (e.g., mockup of product, checked weight, workflow).
- Provided contracts and separate estimates to customers, created line-item breakdowns of the project, and assigned the tasks and responsibilities to the appropriate production platform within the organization.
- Manage a high-performing team in a heavily cross-functional operations organization.
- Develop, coach, and mentor team members.
- Lead review presentations with Cross-functional partner leadership to highlight supply planning initiatives.
- Establish expertise in Product Data Operations as it relates to Supply Planning functions and work closely
 with an extensive amount of cross functional partners.
- Create and execute a strategy to support the end-to-end processes for team resource tracking, invoicing, and financial reporting.
- Utilize self-starting, intellectually curious, and creative behavior while executing through ambiguous scenarios.
- Work with a portfolio of global external and internal partners.

	_
TECHNICAL	PROFICIENCIES
IFURNIUAL	PRUFICIFICIES

- Microsoft Office: Excel, Outlook, Word, PowerPoint, MS Project
- Java
- Python
- Oracle DBMS

- Microsoft Server
- Web Services (XAMP, Apache, SQL, MYSQL)
- ERP Solution, Open-Source Technology
- Networks and Information Security
- Linux (LAMP Technology)

EDUCATION

- MIDDLESEX COLLEGE; ASSOCIATES DEGREE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE & INFORMATION SYSTEMS -2020
- MASSACHUSETTS INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY (MIT); PG CERTIFICATE IN ENTREPRENEURSHIP AND INNOVATION - 2018
- NATIONAL COMPUTING CENTER, LONDON; PGD IN STRATEGIC BUSINESS INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY - 2009
- FEDERAL UNIVERSITY OF TECHNOLOGY AKURE PGD IN MECHANICAL ENGINEERING 2006 PRODUCTION OPTIONS
- YABA COLLEGE OF TECHNOLOGY, BACHELORS MECHANICAL ENGINEERING 2003 DESIGNS OPTIONS